Zhaoxuan Tan

Address: Pengkang Building 206, 28 Xianning W Rd, Xi'an, China

Email: tanzhaoxuan@stu.xjtu.edu.cn, tanzx9@gmail.com

Homepage: zhaoxuan.info

Last updated: October 11, 2022

Research Interests

I am broadly interested in graph neural networks, knowledge graph, social network analysis, natural language processing, and graph mining in general. My previous research includes Twitter bot detection, knowledge graph completion, and graph representation learning. Now I'm working on large-scale knowledge graphs reasoning.

Education

Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, Shaanxi, China (member of the C9 league in China) 2019.08 - present B.S. in Computer Science and Technology

GPA: 89.1(+3)/100, top 6% Advisor: Prof. Minnan Luo

Publications (* indicates equal contribution)

[1] Contrastive Learning with Graph Context Modeling for Sparse Knowledge Graph Completion.

Zhaoxuan Tan, Zilong Chen, Shangbin Feng, Qingyue Zhang, Qinghua Zheng, Jundong Li, Minnan Luo. arXiv preprint arXiv:2208.07622, 2022.

[2] TwiBot-22: Towards Graph-Based Twitter Bot Detection.

Shangbin Feng*, **Zhaoxuan Tan***, Herun Wan*, Ningnan Wang*, Zilong Chen*, Binchi Zhang*, Qinghua Zheng, Wenqian Zhang, Zhenyu Lei, Shujie Yang, Xinshun Feng, Qingyue Zhang, Hongrui Wang, Yuhan Liu, Yuyang Bai, Heng Wang, Zijian Cai, Yanbo Wang, Lijing Zheng, Zihan Ma, Jundong Li, Minnan Luo. *In Proceedings of the NeurIPS Datasets and Benchmarks Track, 2022.*

[3] PAR: Political Actor Representation Learning with Social Context and Expert Knowledge.

Shangbin Feng, **Zhaoxuan Tan**, Zilong Chen, Peisheng Yu, Qinghua Zheng, Xiaojun Chang, Minnan Luo.

In Proceedings of Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2022.

[4] Heterogeneity-aware Twitter Bot Detection with Relational Graph Transformers.

Shangbin Feng, Zhaoxuan Tan, Rui Li, Minnan Luo.

In Proceedings of AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2022. [15% acceptance rate]

[5] KALM: Knowledge-Aware Integration of Local, Document, and Global Contexts for Long Document Understanding.

Shangbin Feng, Zhaoxuan Tan, Wenqian Zhang, Zhenyu Lei, Yulia Tsvetkov.

arXiv preprint arXiv:2210.04105, 2022.

[6] AHEAD: A Triple Attention Based Heterogeneous Graph Anomaly Detection Approach.

Shujie Yang, Binchi Zhang, Shangbin Feng, **Zhaoxuan Tan**, Qinghua Zheng, Ziqi Liu, Minnan Luo. arXiv preprint arXiv:2208.08200, 2022.

Honors and Awards

AAAI Student Scholarship, Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence	2022
National Second Prize, Contemporary Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling	2021
Scholarship for Outstanding Students, Second Prize (rank $11/164$), Xi'an Jiaotong University	2021
Dean's List, Xi'an Jiaotong University	2021

Top Project Runner Up, NUS SoC Summer Workshop	2021	
Honorable Mentioned Prize (top 15%), Mathematical Contest in Modeling (MCM)	2021	
Scholarship for Outstanding Students, Second Prize (rank $39/1200$), Xi'an Jiaotong University		
First Prize in Shaanxi Province, Contemporary Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling		
Dean's List, Xi'an Jiaotong University	2020	
Experience		
Research Assistant @ National University of Singapore	2022.08 - present	
Work on a project that aims to understand humans' interaction with chatbots.		
Advisor: Renwen Zhang @ National University of Singapore, Singapore		
Research Intern, Knowledge Engineering Group (KEG), Tsinghua University	2022.04 - present	
Large-scale knowledge graph completion and reasoning with language model.		
Advisor: Yuxiao Dong @ Tsinghua University, China		
Research Assistant, Luo lab Undergraduate Division (LUD), Xi'an Jiaotong University	2021.08 - present	
Member of the LUD lab , focusing on graph-based Twitter bot detection and knowledge graph embedding		
learning. One second-author conference paper of Twitter bot detection got accepted at AAAI 2022.		
Advisor: Minnan Luo @ Xi'an Jiaotong University, China		
Summer Workshop, National University of Singapore (virtual)	2021.05 - 2021.07	
Attend lectures in AI analytics and IoT, build a Twitter bot detection demo.		
Advisor: Lek Hsiang Hui @ National University of Singapore, Singapore		
Information-technology Talent Program, Xi'an Jiaotong University	2020.11 - 2021.10	
Bulid a UAV formation control system, learn basic reinforcement learning algorithm.		
Advisor: Liangjun Ke @ Xi'an Jiaotong University, China		
Services		
Reviewer for NeurIPS, Datasets and Benchmarks Track	2022	
Reviewer for Learning on Graphs Conference	2022	
Director of the LUD lab	2022	

Skills

Programming Languages:

-Proficient: Python, MATLAB, C/C++ -Capable: Bash, HTML/CSS, Javascript

Tools and Frameworks: PyTorch, LaTeX, Visual Studio, MobaXTerm, Git, ssh, Vim **Natural Languages:** Mandarin (native), English (fluent), Cantonese (native)